# TINA CAI **UX** Designer

# **ABOUT**

UX designer with experience in UI design and front-end development.

Skilled in communicating with project stakeholders, balancing their needs, and designing solutions within multidisciplinary teams. Committed to tackling problems with a usercentered approach through design thinking, empathy and retrospective.

# **SKILLS**

Competitive Analysis User Reseasrch Persona Development Information Architecture Sketching / Wireframing Prototyping

Storyboarding

**Usability Testing** 

Visual Design

Style Guides

**UI** Animation

Responsive Web Design

HTML / CSS / JavaScript

## **TOOLS**

Figma

Adobe XD

Sketch

Balsamia

Visual Studio Code

GitHub

# CONTACT



Seattle, Washington, USA



(206) 407-4205



tinacai.me



linkedin.com/tinacai97



tinacai1997@gmail.com

# **PROJECTS**

# Payd, E-Wallet App

# UX/UI Design | tinacal.me/payd.html

- Designed an e-wallet app that compiled mobile payment user goals into one platform, reducing the need for multiple financial apps.
- Conducted competitive analyses and user interviews to understand ewallet user needs, resulting in user personas and flows that represented app target audience.
- Tested design solutions with end-users to iterate on 30+ high fidelity wireframes, leading to an interactable prototype and style guide that presented a solution to an all-in-one e-wallet application.

# **Lingually, Language Learning App**

May 2021 - Jun 2021

Jun 2021 - Oct 2021

### UX/UI Design | tinacai.me/lingually.html

- Designed a language app to motivate language learners to practice based on their needs, resulting in a versatile educational tool.
- Researched existing language apps and conducted user interviews to develop a user persona to empathize with and design towards.
- Created a low fidelity prototype then assessed it by performing usability tests on app functionality with end-users, leading to improved wireframes ready for mid-fidelity.

# **EDUCATION**

# **User Experience Design Certificate**

May 2021 - Dec 2021

CareerFoundry | Online Bootcamp

Front End Specialization

### **B.S. Electrical and Computer Engineering**

Sep 2015 - Jun 2019

University of Washington | Seattle, WA

Power Design Concentration

## **EXPERIENCE**

# **Electrical Engineer**

Jan 2020 - Apr 2021

### Arup | Seattle, WA

- Designed electrical power systems based on client needs and available equipment and supply to new and existing buildings, producing electrical power and lighting plans for 13 building projects.
- Collaborated with project stakeholders on a regular basis to balance working on multidisciplinary projects, delivering 100+ deliverables on time and moving projects to the next design phase.

# **Electrical Engineering Intern**

Jun 2019 - Sep 2019

## KATERRA | Seattle, WA

- Designed electrical power and lighting plans for a three 4-story multifamily residential project, successfully seeing a project design delivlerable through and on time.
- Coordinated with internal architects and project members to modify electrical plans based on owner needs, room layout, and standards, resulting in a design package of 80+ code compliant drawings.